<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home  on Sebastian Sciarra</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home  on Sebastian Sciarra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://example.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Note. Generated using a variety of artificial intelligence tools for image processing and image generation (specifically, fotor, DALL-E2, and Deep Dream Generator) I&amp;rsquo;m Sebastian Sciarra and I am currently a PhD candidate in the Industrial-Organizational Psychology program at the University of Guelph. I am largely interested in statistics, coding, and machine learning, and have used my time as a graduate student learning a variety of topics in these areas while completing my dissertation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Resources</title>
      <link>https://example.com/mlresources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/mlresources/</guid>
      <description>This is a list of useful resources I have stumbled upon while completing my dissertation and learning about machine learning, statistics, and programming.
Courses and Lecture Series&#39; CS 47980 - Machine Learning for Intelligent Systems Bloomberg - Foundations of Machine Learning Computer Science 25300 / 35300 &amp;amp; Statistics 27700 - Mathematical Foundations of Machine Learning CS 156 - Learning Systems CS 485/685 - Machine Learning Theory: this is a more advanced course that I personally would only encourage taking after taking at least two of the above courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability, Likelihood, and Maximum Likelihood Estimation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/technical_content/mle_em_algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/technical_content/mle_em_algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Explanation of post</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of p-hacking on false positive rates</title>
      <link>https://example.com/simulation_exps/phacking/p_hacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/simulation_exps/phacking/p_hacking/</guid>
      <description>$$ \gamma $$
#this is a comment more comment print(&amp;#39;my website my website my website my website my website my website my website my website my website my website my website my website my website my website my website&amp;#39;) print(1 + 2) print(&amp;#39;another&amp;#39;) </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
